

# ALEXANDER TRESPALACIOS

Telecommunications Engineering Junior Software Developer Copacabana - Colombia

jrios

jrios714@soyudemedellin.edu.co

€.

+573108202461



https://ijrios.github.io/



https://github.com/ijrios

# **ABOUT ME**

My academic training and experience are enriched with solid skills in various areas such as Machine learning, supervised learning, cluster analysis, .NET developer, Python developer. Knowledgeable in Django Rest Framework, React Js, Python Flask, Selenium, C# and Java (SprintBoot and Console Aplication). Thus reflecting my versatility and adaptability to address technical challenges.

# **PROJECTS**

- CardioVigilant AI: Solution to the challenge chosen for the data science hackathon. – Flask Pyhton, Machine Learning
- Systema IoT Retrofit Aquae Intelligentes Tank Python
- Bookstore (Reviews Reservations) OOP Java
- Bancolombia Operational Excellence website .Net MVC
- IoT Retrofit home automation control system for sliding windows.

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish
English
Latín

# **SKILLS**

.NET
C#
Python
SQL
Mach. Learn.
React JS

#### REFERENCES

Jeeny Cuantindioy
Full-time Professor
Phone: 3002503586

E-mail: Jenny.cuantindioy@udea.edu.co

Jakeline Ramos Session Boss Phone: 3016603239 E-mail: jaramos@bancolombia.com.co Mario Alberto Luna Full-time Professor Phone: 3002072673 E-mail: mluna@udem.com.co

Felix Aviléz <sub>Lawyer</sub>

Phone: 3012944917 E-mail: <u>felixavilez17@gmail.com</u>

# **EDUCATION**

2016 - 2024 Medellín, Colombia

Engineer's degree, Telecommunications Engineering University of Medellín



## **EXPERIENCES**

#### LAMBDA ANALYTICS S.A.S

Junior Software Developer August 2024 – Present Medellín, Colombia

- Django Rest Framework, Python developer
- Process automation, Selenium, Request
- React js, Git and Postgresql
- Knime

#### **BANCOLOMBIA**

Engineer Intern January 2024 – August 2024 Medellín, Colombia

- Net Developer ASP.NET MVC and Layered architecture, C#, SQL
- Bank process automation, developer. Automate the monitoring and loading of Bancolombia's installed capacity and and other projects

### **UNIVERSITY OF MEDELLIN**

Academic Mentor July 2023 – Dec 2023 Medellín, Colombia

- · Development of machine learning processes in Python
- Digital holographic images applying image processing
- Convolutional neural network architecture with Python



# **WINNERS**

HACKATHON DATA SCIENCE - FIRST PLACE: «CardioVigilant\_AI»
Institución Universitaria Pascual Bravo Y Ruta N